<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Packer on Things I find interesting</title>
    <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/tags/packer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Packer on Things I find interesting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sdorsett.github.io/tags/packer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripted Packer build, ovftool export and Vagrant .box file creation</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-28-scripted-packer-build-and-export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-28-scripted-packer-build-and-export/</guid>
      <description>This is the seventh in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In the last post we covered using ovftool to convert Packer generated virtual machines into Vagrant .box files. I promised to show you a better way of exporting and creating the Vagrant .box files, so in this post we will be combining the following items in one script:
 Kicking off the Packer build of a specific template Exporting the Packer generated virtual machine Creating the necessary metadata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ovftool to convert Packer generated virtual machines into Vagrant .box files</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-27-using-ovftool-to-export-packer-generated-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-27-using-ovftool-to-export-packer-generated-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>This is the sixth in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In the last post we covered copying our existing CentOS 6.7 template and adding the Puppet agent in order to generate a new Packer template. In this post we will be covering how to use ovftool to convert Packer generated virtual machines into Vagrant .box files. This post will be going over the manual steps on purpose, since I feel it will make more sense when we start to cover automating the steps that you can already performed by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying our existing CentOS 6.7 template and adding the Puppet agent</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-26-copy-our-existing-template-and-add-the-puppet-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-26-copy-our-existing-template-and-add-the-puppet-agent/</guid>
      <description>This is the fifth in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In the last post we covered creating a Packer template for installing CentOS 6.7 with vmtools. In this post we will be basing a new Packer template on the one we created last post and add installing the Puppet Enterprise 3.8.2 agent.
This is an older version of the Puppet Enterprise agent, but it will let us create a Vagrant .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating our first Packer template for installing CentOS 6.7 with vmtools</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-25-creating-a-packer-template-for-installing-centos-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-25-creating-a-packer-template-for-installing-centos-67/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In the last two posts we covered installing a ESXi virtual machine for use with Packer and Setting up Packer, ovftool and Apache web server on a CentOS virtual machine. In this post we will be putting all this prep work to use in order to install a CentOS 6.7 image using Packer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Packer, ovftool and Apache web server on a CentOS virtual machine</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-24-installing-packer-and-ovftool-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-24-installing-packer-and-ovftool-on-centos/</guid>
      <description>This is the third in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In the last post we setup a ESXi virtual machine that would be the target for creating Packer images. In order to follow along with this post you will need two things:
 A fresh CentOS virtual machine on which we will install Packer - I&amp;rsquo;m using CentOS 6.6 minimal install named &amp;ldquo;packer-centos&amp;rdquo; with 2 vCPU, 4GB of memory and a 100GB virtual hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a ESXi 6.0 virtual machine for use with Packer</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-23-installing-esxi-virtual-machine-for-packer-depolyment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-23-installing-esxi-virtual-machine-for-packer-depolyment/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in a series of posts on using a Packer pipeline to generate Vagrant .box files.
In order to begin using Packer to create images, we will first need to lay the &amp;ldquo;virtual&amp;rdquo; ground work. Packer can create virtual machine images on a wide variety of virtualization or cloud platforms, but since I work for VMware I have been using the ESXi hypervisor.
 This post will be covering installing ESXi as a virtual machine on a vSphere cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a pipeline for creating Packer .box files</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-22-pipeline-for-creating-packer-box-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2015-12-22-pipeline-for-creating-packer-box-files/</guid>
      <description>Recently at work, the vCloud Air Zombie team has been using Packer to generate Vagrant templates for use in development and testing. I have previously covered how to use Packer to create create a .box template for use with Vagrant, but I thought it might be useful to others to demonstrate how we are using Packer to create images.
This will be the first of several blog posts in which I intend to cover:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using packer on OS X to create an ESXi .box template for vagrant deployment</title>
      <link>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2014-12-28-getting-packer-installed-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdorsett.github.io/post/2014-12-28-getting-packer-installed-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently working on using packer to create vagrant .box files rather than manually creating them as I documented in a previous post. For this post I will be using fusion and the vagrant vmware provider, each of which have an associated cost, but I will cover a free alternative using packer and CentOS in a future post.
Several github projects by gosddc have helped me in getting packer up and running on my Macbook:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>